Ford Foundation records, Building Services, Ford Foundation artwork photographs FA1723
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Building Services, Ford Foundation artwork photographs
1963-1969, 2019
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1723
2.66 Cubic Feet 7 Hollinger boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas. During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files, and officers' papers were transferred to and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011.
This material was transferred to the RAC in 2019 and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2019:105.
Accessions continue as necessary.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of photographs and associated materials that document the art collection the Ford Foundation acquired between 1966 and 1967 through the Art Purchase Program. The collection is comprised of one series of artwork photograph files. These files generally contain photographs, photograph negatives, and invoices that regard a piece of art (or a set of art) that the Foundation purchased for the New York City headquarters building it opened in 1967. The files provide photographic evidence of the artwork, information about the artist who created it, information about the material details and dimensions of the artwork, and information about the purchase of the item. They are organized by the name of the artist.
Archival documentation left in the containers originally housing the records indicate that the Ford Foundation's Building Services department maintained the files. Building Services was a part of the Logistical Services unit in the Foundation's Division of Administration.
Invoices and a small amount of correspondence in the files show how Yale University Art Gallery Director Andrew Carnduff Ritchie purchased the art on behalf of the Ford Foundation. The Foundation purchased art from various galleries and art dealers in San Francisco, New York, London, Paris, Zurich, Lucerne, and Amsterdam. This art was created by artists of American, Dutch, English, French, German, Italian, Japanese, Russian, and Spanish origin, among others. Some of these artists include Marc Chagall, Salvador Dali, Eugene Delacroix, Henri Matisse, and Pablo Picasso.
A few art books and gallery exhibition descriptions can be found in the collection. There is also a record created long after the art collection that the photograph files describe was acquired by the Ford Foundation. This letter from 2019 inquired about a piece of art that had once been part of the collection but was now in the possession of the correspondent.
Arrangement
Collection consists of one series. Files within that series are arranged alphabetically by artist last name.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series 1. Artwork photograph files, 1963-1969, 2019
Biographical / Historical
In March 1966 the Ford Foundation appointed Andrew Carnduff Ritchie (1907-1978), Director of the Yale University Art Gallery, as a consultant to select and purchase works of art for the Foundation's new headquarters building in New York City. The appointment was to last approximately one year.
Related Materials
Files maintained by Yale University Art Gallery Director Andrew Carnduff Ritchie about the Ford Foundation's Art Purchase Program can be accessed here: FA762, Ford Foundation records, Art Purchase Program
Ford Foundation; Art
- Artwork photograph files, 1963-1969, 2019; 1; 2.66 Cubic Feet About 7 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Series chiefly contains invoices, photographs, and photograph negatives documenting the Ford Foundation's purchases of various pieces of art between 1966 and 1967. File titles were reduced to only include the artist's name and the title of the artwork. The more descriptive information included on the back of the photographs and on the original envelopes containing the photograph negatives is noted at file level scope and contents notes. This information encompasses artist biographic data (nationality and birth and death dates), material details, item dimensions, and the name of the entity from which the art was purchased. Some files in the series also contains materials like correspondence, gallery exhibition descriptions, and art books.
  - Absolon, John - The Colebrookdale Dome, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Art Description:
    John Absolon (English, 1815-1895)
    The Colebookdale Dome, title page Recollections of the Great Exhibition of 1851
    Watercolor, 15 x 11" (Sight)
    Purchased from David Magee, San Francisco, California
  - Absolon, John - View in the North Transept, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Art description:
    View in the North Transept, from Recollections of the Great Exhibition of 1851
    Watercolor, 10 3/4 x 14 3/4" (Sight)
  - Allom, Thomas - Travellers Boarding the Channel Steamer at Dover, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Thomas Allom (English, 1804-1872)
    Travellers Boarding the Channel Steamer at Dover
    Brush and brown ink over pencil lines, 8 1/2 x 15 1/2"
    Purchased from Bernard Houthakker, Amsterdam, Netherlands
  - American, 19th Century - California and Oregon stage lines material, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    American, 19th Century
    California and Oregon stage lines material, 1862-1867
    23 1/2 x 29 1/2"
    Purchased from John Howell, San Francisco, California
  - American, 19th Century - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Salt Lake City, Utah, 1891
    Lithograph, 26 x 44 1/2"
  - Arnout, Louis-Jules - St. Petersbourg lithographs, 1967; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Louis-Jules, Arnout (French, 1814-?)
    - St. Petersbourg: Colonne Alexandrine, et l'Hotel de l'Etat Major Color lithograph, 9 1/2 x 12 1/2"
    - St. Petersbourg: Palais du Duc le Leuctemberg Color lithograph, 10 x 14"
    - St. Petersbourg: Cathedrale de N.D. de Kasan Color lithograph, 10 1/4 x 13 3/4"
    - St. Petersbourg: Place du Palais Imperial Color lithograph, 10 x 13 1/2"
    - St. Petersbourg: Pont de Troizkoi Color lithograph, 10 x 13 1/4"
    Purchased from B. Weinreb, London, United Kingdom
  - Arp, Jean - Presque vase et fleur, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Jean Arp (French, born Germany 1888)
    Presque vase et fleur, 1955
    Color lithograph, 19 5/8 x 17"
    Purchased from Berggruen, Paris, France
  - Bassen, Bartholomeus van - Interior of a Palace, 1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Bartholomeus van Bassen (Dutch, 1590-1652)
    Interior of a Palace
    Oil on panel, 17 x 24 1/4"
    Purchased from H.L. Shickman, New York, New York
  - Beham, Hans Sebald - The Fountain of Youth, 1967; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Hans Sebald Beham (German, 1500-1550)
    The Fountain of Youth
    Woodcut, 14 7/8 x 43 1/4"
    Purchased from August Laube, Zurich, Switzerland
  - Behrens, Peter - Storm, 1967; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Peter Behrens (German, 1868-1940)
    Storm, 1896
    Color woodcut, 19 1/2 x 25 1/2"
    Purchased from L'Art Ancien, Zurich, Switzerland
  - Bichebois, Louis Philippe-Alphonse - St. Petersbourg lithographs, 1967; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Louis Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois (French, 1801-1850)
    - St. Petersbourg: Vue du Pont et de l'Eglise d'Isaac Color lithograph, 10 x 13 1/2"
    - St. Petersbourg: Vue de la Bourse Color lithograph, 10 x 13 1/4"
  - Biliverti, Giovanni - Tobias Kneeling Before the Angel, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Giovanni Biliverti (Italian, 1576-1644)
    Tobias Kneeling Before the Angel
    Red chalk, 15 1/2 x 11" (Sight)
    Purchased from Charles E. Slatkin, Inc. Galleries, New York, New York
  - Bison, Giuseppe Bernardino - Design for a Mural for an Italian Villa, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Giuseppe Bernardino Bison (Italian, 1762-1844)
    Design for a Mural for an Italian Villa, circa 1790
    Pen and watercolor, 14 1/8 x 14 3/4"
    Purchased from Yvonne Ffrench, London, United Kingdom
  - Bohemian, Anonymous, 15th Century - Illuminated manuscript page, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Bohemian, Anonymous, 15th Century
    Illuminated manuscript page
    Parchment, 27 1/2 x 17 3/4"
  - Bonnard, Pierre - Aux Champs Elysees, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Pierre Bonnard (French, 1867-1947)
    Aux Champs Elysees
    Etching, 13 1/8 x 10 1/4"
  - Boucher, Francois - Heads of a Young Woman and an Old Man, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Francois Boucher (French, 1703-1770)
    Heads of a Young Woman and an Old Man
    Charcoal and white chalk, 10 1/8 x 15 1/4"
    Purchased from Christopher Powney, London, United Kingdom
  - Boudin, Eugene - Calvaire a Louganna, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Eugene Boudin (French, 1824-1898)
    Calvaire a Louganna
    Watercolor, 5 1/2 x 7 1/4"
    Purchased from Hector Brame, Paris, France
  - Bourdelle, Emile Antoine - Crouching Bather, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of photographs and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Emile Antoine Bourdelle (French, 1861-1929)
    Crouching Bather, 1906-07
    Bronze, 10 ½" high
    Cast No. 6
  - Bourdelle, Emile Antoine - Sappho, 1964-1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Sappho, 1887-1925
    Bronze, 11" high
    Cast No. 5
  - Boys, Thomas Shotter - Original Views of London as It Is, undated; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Thomas Shotter Boys (English, 1803-1874)
    Original Views of London as It is, 1842
    - 1. Frontispiece: Doorway, Temple Church Colored lithograph, 18 5/8 x 13"
    - 2. Mansion House, Cheapside Colored lithograph, 12 1/2 x 16 3/4"
    - 3. The Tower and Mint from Great Tower Hill Colored lithograph, 7 3/4 x 17"
    - 4. The Custom House Colored lithograph, 16 3/4 x 12 3/8"
    - 5. London Bridge from Southwark Bridge Colored lithograph, 7 x 17 7/8"
    - 6. London from Greenwich Colored lithograph, 11 3/8 x 17"
    - 7. Blackfriars from Southwark Bridge Colored lithograph, 6 7/8 x 17 3/4"
    - 8. Westminster from Waterloo Bridge Colored lithograph, 6 7/8 x 18"
    - 9. Westminster Abbey Hospital Colored lithograph, 12 1/2 x 17 1/2"
    - 10. Board of Trade, Whitehall from Downing Street Colored lithograph, 16 1/2 x 12 1/2"
    - 11. Buckingham Palace from St. James''s Park Colored lithograph, 9 5/8 x 17 1/2"
    - 12. North Front to James's Palace, from Cleveland Row Colored lithograph, 15 3/4 x 12 1/2"
    - 13. The Club Houses Pall Mall Colored lithograph, 12 1/4 x 17 5/8"
    - 14. The House Guards from St. James's Park Colored lithograph, 9 5/8 x 17 3/4"
    - 15. Hyde Park Corner Colored lithograph, 12 x 16 3/4"
    - 16. Hyde Park near Grosvenor Gate Color lithograph, 9 5/8 x 18 3/8"
    - 17. Piccadilly looking towards the City Colored lithograph, 12 1/2 x 16 7/8"
    - 18. Regent Street looking towards the Quadrant Colored lithograph, 12 x 16 1/2"
    - 19. Regent Street looking towards the Duke of York's column Colored lithograph, 12 1/8 x 17 7/8"
    - 20. Entry to the Strand from Charing Cross Colored lithograph, 10 5/8 x 17 5/8"
    - 21. The Strand Colored lithograph, 16 3/4 x 12 3/8"
    - 22. Temple Bar, from the Strand Colored lithograph, 16 3/4 x 12 3/8"
    - 23. St. Dunstans Fleet Street Colored lithograph, 16 3/4 x 21 3/8"
    - 24. St. Paul's from Ludgate Hill Colored lithograph, 17 x 12 1/4"
    - 25. Guildhall Color lithograph, 11 5/8 x 15 3/4"
    - 26. The Bank, looking towards the Mansion House Color lithograph, 16 3/4 x 12 3/8"
  - Brancusi, Constantin - The Artist's Studio, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Constantin Brancusi (Rumanian, 1876-1957)
    The Artist's Studio, circa 1921
    Pen, 14 x 10 1/2" (Sight)
    Purchased from Hanover Gallery, London, United Kingdom
  - Buys, Jacobus - The Proposal, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Jacobus Buys (Dutch, 1724-1801)
    The Proposal
    Watercolor, 11 5/8 x 10 1/8"
  - Caylo, Nicolino - Views of the Great Fire in New York, 1967; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Nicolino Calyo (American, born Italy, 1799-1884)
    - View of the Great Fire in New York, December 16th and 17th, 1835 Mixed media, 12 1/2 x 19" (Sight)
    - View of the Ruins After the Great Fire in New York, December 16th and 17th, 1835 Mixed media, 12 1/2 x 19" (Sight)
    Purchased from Kennedy Galleries, New York, New York
  - Cambiaso, Luca - The Meeting of Isaac and Rebecca/Sketches of two heads, etc., 1966; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Luca Cambiaso (Italian, 1527-1585)
    - The Meeting of Isaac and Rebecca (recto) Pen and wash, 5 5/8 x 10"
    - Sketches of two heads, etc. (verso) Pen and wash, 5 5/8 x 10"
    Purchased from Mathias Komor, New York, New York
  - Cassell, J.H. - The Dockyard at Fare Ute Point, Tahiti, with the H.B.M. Frigate Calypso, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Art description: J. H. Cassell (English) The Dockyard at Fare Ute Point, Tahiti, with the H.B.M Frigate Calypso Watercolor, 13 1/2 x 28" Purchased from John Howell, San Francisco, California
  - Chagall, Marc - Les Cyclistes, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Marc Chagall (Russian, born 1889)
    Les Cyclistes, 1956
    Lithograph, 26 x 19 3/4"
  - Chagall, Marc - Moise et les tables de la loi, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Moise et les tables de la loi, 1962
    Color lithograph, 26 x 20"
  - Chagall, Marc - Paravent, 1963-1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Paravent, 1963
    Color lithograph, screen in 4 sections, 58 x 75" overall
    Purchased from Contemporary Art Establishment, Vaduz, Liechtenstein
  - Chagall, Marc - Vase de fleurs a l'ananas, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Vase de fleurs a l'ananas, 1964
    Color lithograph, 30 x 22"
    Purchased from Berggruen, Paris
  - Chagall, Marc - Les Maries au soleil jaune, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Les Maries au soleil jaune, 1965
    Original color monotype, 11 3/4 x 15 3/4"
    Purchased from Galerie Rosengart, Lucerne
  - Chagall, Marc - Les Amoureux devant la fenetre, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Les Amoureux devant la fenetre
    India ink and wash, 26 3/8 x 20 3/8" (Sight)
    Purchased from Galerie Rosengart, Lucerne, Switzerland
  - Chillida, Eduardo - Untitled, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Eduardo Chillida (Spanish, born 1924)
    Untitled, 1959
    Ink, 17 1/4 x 21 3/4"
    Purchased from Marlborough-Gerson, New York, New York
  - Cortona, Pietro de - Mythological Scene, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Pietro de Cortona (Italian, 1596-1669)
    Mythological Scene
    Pen, heightened with white, 7 1/2 x 10 1/3"
  - Cruickshank, George - Entente Un-cordial, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    George Cruickshank (English, 1792-1872)
    Entente Un-cordial
    Watercolor, 7 1/8 x 14 3/4" (Sight)
    Purchased from Spink and Son, Ltd., London, United Kingdom
  - Cuming, Richard - Tintern Abbey, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Richard Cuming (English, 19th Century)
    Tintern Abbey, 1800
    Watercolor, 22 x 15"
  - Dali, Salvador - Place de la Concorde, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Salvador Dali (Spanish, born 1904)
    Place de la Concorde, 1963
    Color etching, 17 1/2 x 23"
  - Dali, Salvador - Escorial, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Escorial, 1964
  - Daniell, Thomas - Views in Calcutta, 1967; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Thomas Daniell (English, 1749-1840)
    Views in Calcutta, 1786-1788
    - No. 1 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 13/16"
    - No. 2 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 3 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 4 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 5 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 6 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 7 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 1/2 x 20 1/4"
    - No. 8 Hand-colored aquatint, 16 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 9 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 10 Hand-colored aquatint, 16 x 21"
    - No. 11 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 3/4"
    - No. 12 Hand-colored aquatint, 15 3/4 x 20 5/8"
  - Delacroix, Eugene - A Boar (Sanglier), 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Eugene Delacroix (French, 1798-1863)
    A Boar (Sanglier)
    Black chalk, 9 x 13"
    Purchased from Schaeffer Galleries, New York, New York
  - Delacroix, Eugene - Study after Figures of a Roman Sarcophagus, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Study after Figures of a Roman Sarcophagus, 1824/1825
    Pen and ink, 9 7/8 x 15 1/2"
    Purchased from Dr. Willi Raeber, Basel, Switzerland
  - Dolby, C.T. - The Agricultural Court, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    C.T. Dolby (English, 19th Century)
    The Agricultural Court (Messers. Garrett and Sons Stand) from Recollections of the Great Exhibition of 1851
  - Durer, Albrecht - The Siege of a Fortress, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Albrecht Durer (German, 1471-1528)
    The Siege of a Fortress, 1527
    Woodcut, 9 x 28 1/2"
  - Dutch, 18th Century - Magnum Mare del Zur cum Insula California, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Dutch, 18th Century
    Magnum Mare del Zur cum Insula California
    Mao, 21 1/2 x 25 1/2"
    Purhased from John Howell, San Francisco, California
  - English, 18th Century - A New Map of North America, with the West India Islands, 1966; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    English, 18th Century
    A New Map of North America, with the West India Islands, 1794
    - Map, 43 x 47 1/2" (top left section)
    - Map, 43 x 47 1/2" (bottom far right section)
    - Map, 43 x 47 1/2" (bottom near right section)
    - Map, 43 x 47 1/2" (bottom near left section)
    - Map, 43 x 47 1/2" (bottom far left section)
    Purchased from John Howell, San Francisco
    One photograph appears to be missing from the set.
  - English, Anonymous, 19th Century - The Collier, 1966; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    English, Anonymous, 19th Century
    The Collier, from Walker's Costume of Yorkshire, 1813
    Hand-colored aquatint, 8 1/4 x 12 1/4"
  - English, 19th Century - Hong Kong, 1967; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Standidge and Co. (English, 19th Century)
    Hong Kong. From a Painting by a Chinese Artist (after I.C. Bourne), 1846
    Lithograph, 16 1/4 x 23" (Sight)
    The photograph that corresponds to the negative in the file can be found in Miscellaneous artwork, 1967-1968, Box 7, Folder 224-225
  - English, Anonymous, 19th Century - "Fowler" Showman's Engine/Engine by Robert Bridson and Son, Neston, 1966; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "Fowler" Showman's Engine Watercolor, 15 x 21 1/2"
    - Engine by Robert Bridson and Son, Neston Watercolor 14 x 20 1/2"
  - Ensor, James - Study for Maurice de Nassau's Funeral Procession, 1966; File contains still images. Images consists of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    James Ensor (Belgian, 1860-1949)
    Study for Maurice de Nassau's Funeral Procession
    Four pencil and crayon drawings, 9 1/2 x 35 1/2"
  - Feininger, Lyonel - Magic Sea, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Lyonel Feininger (American, 1871-1956)
    Magic Sea, 1931
    Watercolor, 12 1/2 x 20 1/2" (Sight)